hvcc.edu 2004-04-08

# Hudson Valley Community College - Privacy Policy

|  |   | 

## Hudson Valley Community College's Privacy Policy  
(Policy Date - 07/18/2002)  
  
---|---|---  
  
### Using [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) \- Our Commitment to Privacy

> At Hudson Valley Community College, we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with Hudson Valley Community College. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/). You can travel through most of [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request. In this respect, it is important that you understand what we do with this information and the steps that we take to protect your privacy. 
> 
> Hudson Valley Community College does not collect any _personal information_ (as that term is defined under the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act) about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail, completing online forms, or completing the online application.
> 
> This policy is consistent with the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

### Information Collected Automatically When You Visit [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/)

> When visiting [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/), Hudson Valley Community College automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:

  * the Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site 
  * the type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running
  * the web page from which the _user_ accessed the current Web page
  * the date and time of the _user's_ request
  * the pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page

> None of the above-mentioned information constitutes _personal information_ as that term is defined by the [Internet Privacy and Security Act](http://assembly.state.ny.us/leg/?ch=17). The information that is automatically collected is used to improve [www.hvcc.edu's](http://www.hvcc.edu/) content and to help Hudson Valley Community College understand how _users_ are interacting with its Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our _users_. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and neither Hudson Valley Community College nor any of its employees, agents or affiliates are authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) for commercial marketing purposes.

### Information Collected When You E-mail [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) or Complete a Transaction

> During your visit to [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) you may send an e-mail to Hudson Valley Community College. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve our Web site, or to forward your message to another SUNY campus for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and neither Hudson Valley Community College nor any of its employees, agents or affiliates are authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.
> 
> During your visit to [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) you may complete a transaction such as an online application or any online forms. The information collected by Hudson Valley Community College, including _personal information_ volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by Hudson Valley Community College and may be disclosed by Hudson Valley Community College for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.
> 
> Hudson Valley Community College does not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. _Users_ are cautioned, however, that the collection of _personal information_ submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access. 

### Disclosure of Information Collected Through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/)

> The collection of information through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. Hudson Valley Community College will only collect _personal information_ through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) or disclose _personal information_ collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) if the _user_ has consented to the collection or disclosure of such _personal information_. The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to Hudson Valley Community College by the _user_ constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Hudson Valley Community College for the purposes for which the _user_ disclosed the information to Hudson Valley Community College.
> 
> However, pursuant to the Internet Security and Privacy Act, Hudson Valley Community College may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of Hudson Valley Community College, or necessary for Hudson Valley Community College to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by federal or state statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the _user_ ; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.
> 
> Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

### Retention of Information Collected Through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/)

> The information collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) is retained by Hudson Valley Community College in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. Information on the requirements of the Arts & Cultural Affairs Law may be found at <http://www.archives.nysed.gov/services/recmgmt.htm>. 
> 
> In general, the Web server logs of Hudson Valley Community College, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of services provided through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/), are retained for one year and then destroyed. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy.

### Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/)

> Any _user_ may submit a request to Hudson Valley Community College's privacy compliance officer to determine whether _personal information_ pertaining to that _user_ has been collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/). Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the _user_. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the _user_ , or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is:
> 
> Director of Communications and Marketing  
>  Hudson Valley Community College  
>  80 Vandenburgh Avenue  
>  Troy, New York 12180
> 
> The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the _personal information_ ; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.
> 
> In the event that Hudson Valley Community College has collected _personal information_ pertaining to a _user_ through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) and that information is to be provided to the _user_ pursuant to the _user's_ request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the _user_ of his or her right to request that the _personal information_ be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in [Section 95 of the Public Officers Law](http://www.tenant.net/Other_Laws/Pubofc/pubofc08.txt).

### Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/)

> Hudson Valley Community College is strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, Hudson Valley Community College limits employee access to _personal information_ collected through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_.
> 
> In addition, Hudson Valley Community College has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.
> 
> For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) for all _users_ , Hudson Valley Community College employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/).

### Cookies

> Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the _user's_ browser on the hard drive of your computer. Temporary session cookies are utilized in certain portions of the [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/) Web site.

### Disclaimer

> The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through [www.hvcc.edu](http://www.hvcc.edu/). 

### Contact Information 

> For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e-mail at [privacy@hvcc.edu](mailto:privacyofficer@hvcc.edu) or by regular mail at:
> 
> Director of Communications and Marketing  
>  Hudson Valley Community College  
>  80 Vandenburgh Avenue  
>  Troy, New York 12180

### Definitions

> The following definitions apply to, and appear in _italics_ , in this policy:
> 
> _Personal Information_ : shall have the same meaning as set forth in the Internet Security and Privacy Act, State Technology Law, Section 202(5) as follows: Any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.
> 
> _User_ : shall have the same meaning as set forth in the Internet Security and Privacy Act, State Technology Law, Section 202(8) as follows: Any natural person who uses the Internet to access a state agency Web site.

Hudson Valley Community College's mission is to provide dynamic, student-centered, comprehensive, and accessible educational opportunities that address the diverse needs of the community.   
PRIVACY POLICY  
Hudson Valley Community College, 80 Vandenburgh Ave., Troy, NY 12180  
(518) 629-HVCC     Toll-free: (877) 325-HVCC

Please send content questions or comments to the Editor at [editor@hvcc.edu](mailto:Editor@hvcc.edu?Subject=Web%20Inquiry).   
Please send technical issues to the Webmaster at [webmaster@hvcc.edu](mailto:Webmaster@hvcc.edu?Subject=Web%20Inquiry). 

Hudson Valley Community College does not discriminate on the basis of age, gender, race or color, national origin, religion, disabling condition, marital status, or sexual orientation.

Hudson Valley Community College, sponsored by [Rensselaer County](http://www.rensco.com/), is part of the [State University of New York](http://www.suny.edu/) system.   
Copyright © 2000 Hudson Valley Community College, ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
